Gosh, you with
with Betrand, Chris said he was a blue
card guy. What what led to that him
being kind of a priority for you guys?
Yeah, and I think Chris has talked about
it, too, right? Wanting to make the
locker room edgier, wanting to improve
toughness, wanting to improve at
competes, right? He does that. He fits
all three categories with the way he
prepares, but also the way he
plays the game.
You know, in terms of special teams, in
terms of his role in the defense, we can
get more into the kind of unique story,
but that's some of just what makes Bryce
a blue card for us. What stood out to
you about just the traits he brings to
the linebacker position? [snorts]
Yeah, you know, I think the instincts
are the best, right? In terms of what he
does, right? They redeem a lot.
And I think, you know, his buying into
special teams early on in his career has
already shown that. But what that
projects to for us in the league and for
us specifically is a big part of what's
going to cause him to succeed.
>> What do you take away from the two sport
two sport stars generally? What was it
that made you tell you Sure. Yeah, I
think a scout can go either way with it,
right? Is it love in the first sport,
right? Or is it love in football, right?
And so spending time with Bryce on that
and picking on that, you know, a little
bit at the senior bowl in my time with
him showed me there's a real passion
there for football, right? I mean, he
had a unique story, right? Walking on to
both the baseball team and the football
team
and kind of seizing that opportunity
with coach Manning there at Oregon,
which is not an easy place to play the
sport.
Is there Can Can Betrand play both Mike
and Will? Does he have that versatility?
Yeah, you can argue that, right? I think
the instincts kind of project a little
more to Mike,
but I think the the instincts also
project a little bit to Will, right?
Because he can he can function in both
roles.
Uh with with McGowin
So, Chris stresses a lot like the need
for special teams or anything. It
doesn't look like he has a very vast
special teams background. So, with him
like Giddens is kind of in the same
boat. Yeah. How do you guys weigh that
kind of a competition between between
Jonathan when special teams play such
like a big role on game days? Yeah, I
think the first thing with Seth is just
you have to project kind of his running
style and the toughness that he brings
and the size he has and how smart he is.
It's kind of a projection base. He's
never played special teams, like you
said. So, it's going to be a valuable
thing for him to develop throughout his
time here to get to that active roster
and make an impact right away for us.
With Seth, how much does he have to vet
the legal stuff from a few years ago?
>> Uh yeah, I mean, we did our due
diligence with it. I know Chris spoke on
it.
I think Seth made an unfortunate
decision early on in his career. He
learned from it.
And I mean, this kid was out of football
for 2 years and
his love for the game never swayed. I
mean, this kid fought to be where he's
at today.
Fortunately fortunate enough to be on
our team and bring some toughness.
With
You got Jaylon, right? Yeah. Yeah. So, I
mean, does he I think Chris said he'll
start in at the interior for now.
Does he
Does he have flexibility across the line
or what do you
>> Yeah, so
he's only played right guard in in in
games. I think he went down in the
senior bowl and showed he did have a
little bit of versatility to play right
tackle. I think we see him as a as a
guard right now early on. If he develops
well at that position, maybe increase
his load to kind of have that
versatility to play on the outside.
Okay.
With Curry
>> the length part the length part of it
Yeah, I mean,
yeah, I mean, the length I mean, this
kid could run. I mean, he's he's got
over 250 lbs of lean mass on him. He ran
in 49s. This kid can open up and run.
He's got quickness and he's tough to to
go through. He's strong as hell. So,
that's one of the most intriguing things
about him in my opinion. You can't run
through him.
Curry,
guy started just one year at Ohio State,
flashed with
big stats.
What what stood out to him most? I know
he's maybe got a little bit of a unique
build, but obviously the production was
clearly there in that tough schedule in
the Big 10 his best year. Yeah, just
looking at his history early on he
produced on special teams there.
Something he took pride in.
Should project well to our level as
well. I mean, there was guys in front of
him. Talking about whether it's second
round picks, third round picks. There's
all there was always guys in front of
him, but whenever he had an opportunity,
he made a play. And then finally this
year he had the starting opportunity. 11
sacks this year. I think over 40
pressures.
I mean
doesn't doesn't always look great, but
this kid is going to give you everything
he's got and he's going to be productive
and he's going to bring pressure to the
quarterback. How does he overcome the
shorter arms that he has? I mean, you
were kind of hitting at it right there.
Like it doesn't always maybe look
pretty, but he clearly is able to to get
some quarterback.
>> Yeah, I mean, he's coached by one of the
best defensive line coaches in college
football, coach Johnson.
And
the the instincts and just his feel for
the game. He knows how to set up tackles
who are longer than him.
Understands angles and all that and just
how to rush. I mean, and just his motor.
It's hard to block a guy 50 snaps and
plays as plays as
hard hard as hell.
With Bryce, what stood out to you from
an IQ standpoint? Cuz it seems like I
mean, being a green dot guy, they got to
trust you to diagnose a lot of different
things and he seemed to be in the right
place most of the time.
Sure. Yeah, I mean,
a lot of people would argue you can't
teach instincts, right? That's a lot of
it's innate, right? But he spends a lot
of time working at it, too, right? He's
always around the building
preparing how he needs to, asking the
right questions, surrounding himself
with the right people.
And let's not be remissed on the fact
that, you know, he's spending half his
time early on at Oregon in two different
buildings, right? Without a full off
season to attribute to football.
So, he he spent a lot of time on his own
to hone that and and and work on that.
And then obviously this past year he was
fully committed to football.